igossip.com 2010-01-02

# Privacy Policy / iGossip

This is the official privacy policy ("Privacy Policy") for igossip.com ("Site," "we," "us," or "our"), an Internet website offered by the parent company ("Parent Company"). iGossip and its Parent Company are committed to respecting the privacy rights of its Users of the Site. We created this Privacy Policy to give you confidence as you visit and use the Site, and to demonstrate our commitment to fair information practices and the protection of privacy. This Privacy Policy governs only the personally identifiable information ("Personal Information") collected by the Site and does not cover any such information collected in any other manner or for any other purpose, unless specifically stated. This Policy is only applicable to the Site, and not to any other websites that you may be able to access from the Site, each of which may have data collection and use practices and policies that differ materially from this Policy. iGossip is hosted in the United States and are intended for and directed to Users in the United States. If you are a User accessing iGossip from the European Union, Asia, or any other region with laws or regulations governing personal data collection, use, and disclosure, that differ from United States laws, please be advised that through your continued use of iGossip, which are governed by U.S. law, this Privacy Notice, and our Terms of Use, you are transferring your personal information to the United States and you consent to that transfer. 

Please direct any questions regarding this Privacy Policy to us by email at: support@igossip.com

1\. NOTICE CONCERNING CHILDREN. We are a general audience site, and do not direct any of our content specifically at children under 13 years of age. We understand and are committed to respecting the sensitive nature of children's privacy online. If we learn or have reason to suspect that a Site User is under age 13, we will promptly delete any personal information in that User's account.

2\. INFORMATION COLLECTION PRACTICES.

2.1. WHAT BASIC INFORMATION DOES IGOSSIP COLLECT?

The operation of the Site may include registration, online surveys, and other online forms that ask Users to provide their names street address, town or city, state, zip code, telephone number, instant-messenger nickname, blog or other personal website URL, date of birth, e-mail address and any other information that would allow someone to identify you or contact you. Personal Information also includes information about your personal preferences, survey responses and your transactions or relationship with us. In addition to your name and contact information, we will also collect and maintain information about your computer's internet address and website which may have referred or directed you to the Site (e.g., the referring URL). 

2.2. User Profile Information. iGossip collects user submitted information such as name, email address, and age to authenticate Users and to send notifications to those Users relating to iGossip Service. iGossip also collects other profile data including but not limited to: personal interests, profile pictures, gender, age, and geographical location in order to assist Users in finding and communicating with each other.

iGossip also logs non-personally-identifiable information including IP address, profile information, aggregate user data, cookie information, and browser type, from Users and visitors to the site. This data is used to manage the Site, track usage and improve the Site Services. This non-personally-identifiable information may be shared with third-parties to provide more relevant services and advertisements to Users. User IP addresses are recorded for security and monitoring purposes.

User Profile information including Users' pictures, User Names, and first names are displayed to people in order to facilitate user interaction in the iGossip social networking community. Users can change their profile information at any time and can control how other Users and the Service communicates with them. However, once you select a User Name you will not be able to change that User Name provided to us during registration and which is associated with your User Name. Among other things, these kinds of information help us securely identify you as a registered or permitted user of the Site and our features and functions. Additionally you will not be able to change your date of birth without sufficient verification. 

Email addresses are used for the purposes of inviting new friends to join iGossip, to add Users to Users' contacts networks, and to send notifications related to the service. With the exception of inviting friends, adding friends, and notifications, a User's email address is not shared or displayed to people within a User's personal network. Users within a personal network communicate on iGossip with each other through the iGossip Service, without disclosing their email addresses. Users' full names are never directly revealed to other Users. We may also use a User's email address to send updates, a newsletter, or news regarding the service, though Users may choose not to receive email of this type. You may select such options by opting-in at the time of registration or by responding to an offer or invitation at a later date. You will also have the right to opt-out (unsubscribe) or change your preferences at any time by logging in with your User Name and changing the settings in your account. You may also opt- out to particular email communications by responding to that email and using the "unsubscribe" or opt-out procedure included in that communication.

From time to time, iGossip or a partner may sponsor a promotion, sweepstake or contest on iGossip. Users may be asked to provide personal information including name, email address or home address or to answer questions in order to participate. We may transfer personal information to certain ad partners that you have explicitly requested to receive information from. It will be clear at the point of collection who is collecting the personal information and whose privacy statement will apply. 

2.3 Invitations and Other Communications to Non-Users

iGossip Users can invite friends to join the service by sending invitation emails via our automated invitation system. iGossip stores the email addresses that Users provide so that the respondents may be added to the friend's list of the User sending the invitations, and also to send reminders of the invitations. iGossip does not sell these email addresses or use them to send any other communication besides invitations, invitation reminders (up to three (3) per email address). Recipients of invitations from iGossip may contact iGossip to request the removal of their information from our database.

You may prevent iGossip email invitations and other messages from being sent to any email address you control by sending a single email with the subject "BLOCK INVITE" to support@igossip.com. Please note that the email must come from the account you wish to block.

2.4 WHAT ADDITIONAL INFORMATION DOES IGOSSIP COLLECT?

(a) AUTOMATIC COLLECTION. Our servers automatically recognize Users and Visitors' domain names and IP addresses (the number assigned to computers on the Internet). No personal information about you is revealed in this process. The Site may also gather anonymous "traffic data" that does not personally identify you, but that may be helpful for marketing purposes or for improving the services we offer.

(b) COOKIES. iGossip uses cookies to store Users and Visitors' preferences and to record session information, for purposes including ensuring that Users and Visitors are not repeatedly offered the same promotions and advertisements, and to customize newsletter, advertising, and Web page content based on browser type and user profile information. We do not link the information we store in cookies to any personally identifiable information you submit while on our site. You may be able to configure your browser to accept or reject all or some cookies, or notify you when a cookie is set -- each browser is different, so check the "Help" menu of your browser to learn how to change your cookie preferences -- however, you must enable cookies from iGossip in order to use most functions on the site.

3\. USE AND SHARING OF INFORMATION

3.1. WHAT DOES IGOSSIP DO WITH COLLECTED INFORMATION?

(a) PERSONAL INFORMATION. We will not share your personal information with any third parties without your consent, except as necessary to provide you with the services offered by us or to comply with the law. We may use your personal information to verify your identity, to check your qualifications, or to follow up with transactions initiated on the Site. We may also use your contact information to inform you of any changes to the Site, or to send you additional information about iGossip. If you give your permission during the account registration process, we may share your contact information with our business partners or other companies so that they may send you promotional materials.

(b) ANONYMOUS INFORMATION. We use anonymous information to analyze our Site traffic, but we do not examine this information for individually identifying information. In addition, we may use anonymous IP addresses to help diagnose problems with our server, to administer our site, or to display the content according to your preferences. Traffic and transaction information may also be shared with business partners and advertisers on an aggregate and anonymous basis.

(c) USE OF COOKIES. We may use cookies to deliver content specific to your interests, to save your password so you don't have to re-enter it each time you visit our site, or for other purposes. Promotions or advertisements displayed on our site may contain cookies. These cookies allow the ad server to recognize your computer each time they send you an online advertisement. In this way, ad servers may compile information about where you, or others who are using your computer, saw their advertisements and determine which ads are clicked on. This information allows an ad network to deliver targeted advertisements that they believe will be of most interest to you. This privacy statement covers the use of cookies by iGossip and does not cover the use of cookies by any advertisers. We do not have access to or control over information collected by outside advertisers on our site.

(d) DISCLOSURE OF PERSONAL INFORMATION. We may disclose personal information if required to do so by law or in the good-faith belief that such action is necessary to (1) conform to the edicts of the law or comply with legal process served on iGossip or its Parent Company, (2) protect and defend the rights or property of iGossip, its Parent Company, or the Users of the Site, or (3) act under exigent circumstances to protect the safety of the public or Users of the Site.

(e) SALE OF INFORMATION. We do not rent, sell, or share Personally Identifiable Information about you with other people or nonaffiliated companies except to provide products or services you've requested, when we have your permission, or under the following circumstances:

1\. Advertising and marketing agencies to help sell and market products, services and software of ours and our marketing partners;

2\. Technology and other service providers to provide technology and services to us and to you;

3\. Vendors that help us with data analysis, for example for product efficacy studies and market analysis;

4\. We display targeted advertisements based on personal information. Advertisers (including ad serving companies) may assume that people who interact with, view, or click on targeted ads meet the targeting criteria; but We do not provide any personal information to the advertiser when you interact with or view a targeted ad. In order to accommodate changes in our business, we may sell or buy portions of our company or other companies or assets, including the information collected through the Site. The Parent Company or substantially all of its assets are acquired; User information will be one of the assets transferred to the acquirer. In the unlikely event of our bankruptcy, insolvency, reorganization, receivership, or assignment for the benefit of creditors, or the application of laws or equitable principles affecting creditors' rights generally, we may not be able to control how your personal information is treated, transferred, or used.

(f) ACCESS TO INFORMATION. Unfortunately, we do not maintain any procedures for you to review or request changes to the information that we collect about you, except that you may request that we remove all information about you from our database by contacting us in accordance with Section 6.1 below.

4\. SECURITY

The Site has security measures in place to prevent the loss, misuse, and alteration of the information that we obtain from you, but we make no assurances about our ability to prevent any such loss, misuse, to you or to any third party arising out of any such loss, misuse, or alteration. iGossip User accounts are secured by User-created passwords. iGossip takes precautions to insure that User account information is kept private. We use reasonable measures to protect User information that is stored within our database, and we restrict access to User information to those employees who need access to perform their job functions, such as our customer service personnel and technical staff. Please note that we cannot guarantee the security of User account information. Unauthorized entry or use, hardware or software failure, and other factors may compromise the security of User information at any time.

4.1 Phishing

We do not and will not, at any time, request Personally Identifiable Information or other information in a non-secure or unsolicited e-mail or telephone communication. Phishing attacks attempt to steal consumers' personal identity data and financial account credentials. "Phishers" use 'spoofed' e-mails to lead consumers to counterfeit websites designed to trick recipients into divulging Personal Information such as credit card numbers, account u_titles, passwords, and social security numbers. WE DO NOT SEND EMAILS ASKING YOU TO PROVIDE OR CONFIRM SENSITIVE PERSONAL INFORMATION OR YOUR u_title OR PASSWORD! If you receive such email communication, please forward it immediately to the Site's Privacy Administrator, and then immediately delete the fraudulent email from your computer. Identity theft and the practice currently known as phishing are of great concern to us. Safeguarding information to help protect you from identity theft is one of our priorities. For more information about phishing, visit the Federal Trade Commission at http://www.ftc.gov/bcp/conline/pubs/alerts/phishingalrt.htm.

5\. WEBSITE AREAS BEYOND IGOSSIP'S CONTROL

5.1. CHAT ROOMS, MESSAGE BOARDS, USER SUBMISSIONS AND PUBLIC FORUMS

The Site includes the ability to post User Submissions and may include interactive forums such as message boards, Comments, and chat rooms. Please be aware that any information that is disclosed in these areas becomes public information and you should exercise caution when deciding to disclose your personal information.

5.2. THIRD PARTY WEBSITES

The Site may contain links to other websites. If you choose to visit other websites, we are not responsible for the privacy practices or content of those other websites, and it is your responsibility to review the privacy policies at those websites to confirm that you understand and agree with their policies. Our Privacy Policy only governs information collected on iGossip.

6\. CONTACT INFORMATION AND POLICY UPDATES

6.1. CONTACTING US

If you have any questions about this Policy, our practices related to this Site, or if you would like to have us remove your information from our database please feel contact us at support@igossip.com

6.2. UPDATES AND CHANGES

We reserve the right, at any time, to add to, change, update, or modify this Policy, simply by posting such change, update, or modification on the Site and without any other notice to you. Any such change, update, or modification will be effective immediately upon posting on the Site. If, however, we are going to use Users' personally identifiable information in a manner materially different from that stated at the time of collection we will notify by posting a notice of such change on the Site for 30 days. It is your responsibility to review this Policy from time to time to ensure that you continue to agree with all of its terms.
